porschedealer.com 2018-03-19

# Porsche Internet Privacy Policy - Porsche USA

Important Notice: Our Privacy Policy has been updated to give you a better understanding of how we collect, use, and share your information. We have broadened the scope to include the offline collection of information and added more detail regarding automatic collection practices. If you would like a copy of all of the changes, you can request one by contacting us as described in the Contact Us section.

#### Porsche Cars North America, Inc. Privacy Policy

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) describes the information that Porsche Cars North America, Inc. (“Porsche”) collects about you, how we use and share your information, and your choices.

#### Scope

This Privacy Policy applies to information collected about you by or on behalf of Porsche as set forth in the below “Information We Collect” section, including through the websites, mobile applications, and online services or programs where this Privacy Policy is posted or linked (our “Online Services”). Unless otherwise indicated, all references to “Porsche,” “we” or “our” in this Privacy Policy means Porsche Cars North America, Inc. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any of our affiliates, other Porsche companies, or Porsche dealers which are independent third parties.

#### Links, Third-Party Websites, and Social Media Platforms

Our Online Services may contain links to the websites of other Porsche companies, Porsche dealers, or other third parties, as well as to social media platforms such as Facebook or Twitter (“Linked Sites”). Porsche is not responsible and has no liability for the privacy policies or practices of Linked Sites. We recommend that you review the privacy policies of each Linked Site you visit.

#### Outside the U.S.

Our Online Services are for users located exclusively in the United States of America. If you are located outside the United States, please return to www.porsche.com and use the drop down box to find the website for users in your location, but please do not use our Online Services, as the information practices and the terms of this Privacy Policy may or may not comply with foreign law. By using our Online Services, you consent to the use and disclosure of your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and subject to the applicable state and federal laws of the United States.

#### Information We Collect

As used in this Privacy Policy, “Personal Information” means information that can be used to identify a specific individual, such as name, e-mail address, phone number, driver’s license number, or credit card number. “Information” is collectively used herein to refer to both Personal Information and other information that does not identify a specific individual.

Porsche and its third party service providers collect Information about you from a variety of sources, including Personal Information you provide directly to us, Information we collect about you when access and use our Online Services. We also collect your Personal Information from independent Porsche dealers. We may combine any of the Information collected about you for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Information You Provide Us. We collect Personal Information when you:

  * register for the online Porsche Login service;
  * order and/or purchase any of our products or services from us or an independent Porsche dealer;
  * register for any Porsche event or program, including the Porsche Travel Club, Porsche Driving Schools, or webspecials, and/or participate in any event, program, contest, surveys, or other promotion that we may offer from time to time (collectively, “Events”);
  * subscribe to the Porsche Magazine, newsletter, or other communications from us,
  * contact or communicate with us;
  * request information from us;
  * begin or complete the application process for employment by Porsche;
  * access or use Porsche pages or accounts on any third-party social media platforms such as Facebook or Twitter (“Social Media Pages”);
  * provide or submit comments, suggestions, experiences, or other content to us; and/or
  * otherwise interact with us and our Online Services.

#### Information Collected Automatically.

Cookies: Cookies are small text files stored by your browser that allow us to learn more information about your visit or use of our Online Services. We may use cookies to remember your Personal Information, including your registration information, and to track your usage of our Online Services over time. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You have the choice to set your browser to accept or reject cookies. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. You can also learn more about cookies at the following websites:

  * For Microsoft Internet Explorer: http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.mspx
  * For Mozilla Firefox: http://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Options+window+-+Privacy+panel\
  * For Safari: http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1677; and/or
  * http://www.allaboutcookies.org.

Analytics Information: We may use third-party analytics tools, such as Google Analytics, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for our Online Services. These tools collect information sent by your browser or mobile device, including the pages you visit and other information that assists us in improving our Online Services. We collect and use this analytics information in aggregate form.

Log File Information: Log file information is automatically reported by your browser or mobile device each time you access our Online Services. When you use our Online Services, servers may automatically record certain log file information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with Linked Sites, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

Clear Gifs/Web Beacons: When you use our Online Services, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to anonymously track your online usage patterns. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients. This information facilitates more accurate reporting and improvement of our Online Services.

Location Data: When you access our Online Services via a mobile device, we may access, collect, monitor, and/or remotely store information regarding your mobile device, as well as real-time “location data,” which may include GPS coordinates. Location data may convey to us information about how you browse and use our Online Services. You may opt-out from allowing us to have access to your location data by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device, though some features of our Online Services may not function properly if use or availability of location data is impaired or disabled.

Information We Receive From Third Parties. We may receive Information about you from third parties. For example, if you access our Online Services through a third-party connection or log-in (e.g., through Facebook), such third party may pass certain information about your use of its service to us. We may also receive Information you have provided to Porsche dealers, our affiliates, or Porsche clubs. We may also obtain other Information about you such as change of address, contact information, or demographic information from commercially or publicly available sources.

#### How We You Use Your Information

We use your Information, including Personal Information, for a variety of business purposes, including:

  * providing our products and services to you;
  * communicating with you regarding Porsche, and its products, services, and Events;
  * customizing your Porsche experience;
  * creating and managing your online Porsche Login registration;
  * responding to your inquiries, comments, or postings;
  * administering our Events;
  * improving and customizing our Online Services;
  * internal operations such as enhancing our products and services, marketing efforts, and to conduct research and analysis;
  * developing new products and services;
  * processing payments;
  * investigating or settling inquires or disputes;
  * marketing purposes;
  * enforcing our Terms and Conditions Use; and/or
  * protecting the security and integrity of our business and our Online Services.

#### Your Choices In How We Use Your Information

While Porsche may contact you with offers and information concerning Porsche or its products, services or Events, you always have the choice not to receive such items. You may contact us as described in the below Contact Us section to communicate your marketing preferences and request to be removed from marketing lists. You may also request that your Personal Information not be shared with independent Porsche dealerships as part of related marketing and customer care programs (although you should be aware that these dealerships also collect personal data directly from you).

In addition, our Online Services allow you to communicate your marketing preferences as follows (or as otherwise specifically indicated on our Online Services):

  * At the time of registering as a Porsche Online Services user, you will be given a choice whether to receive promotional e-mails from Porsche. Each promotional e-mail you receive from us will provide you a specific opt-out mechanism to allow you to unsubscribe from receipt of these promotional e-mails.
  * By accessing your profile under “Porsche Login” on the Online Services, you may also update your Personal Information in our database or change your marketing preferences.
  * Whether or not registered as a Porsche Online Services user, users who subscribe to the Porsche Magazine or Newsletter may unsubscribe by following the link provided therein, by calling 1-800-PORSCHE or by updating their preferences on our Online Services.

You may contact us as described in the below Contact Us section with any questions or concerns you may have about our privacy practices, including requests to update or correct your Personal Information. Even if you choose not to receive promotional e-mails or mailings from Porsche, we may continue to use your Personal Information in order to contact you in connection with product recalls or other transactional purposes.

#### How We Share Your Information

Porsche does not sell or rent your Personal Information to third parties for their marketing purposes.

We share and disclose your Information as follows:

  * with third parties that provide a variety of services on our behalf, including the development, maintenance, and support of our Online Services, payment processing, communications, and marketing research and analysis;
  * with independent, authorized Porsche dealers for customer care and marketing efforts;
  * with members of our affiliated group of companies for promotional or other purposes;
  * to manage and administer Events;
  * to comply with law, a court order, or other legal process, or in connection with a legal investigation;
  * as may be necessary to protect the rights and interests of Porsche, its affiliates, and authorized Porsche dealers, and our and their respective employees, customers, visitors, users, or any other person or entity;
  * to enforce any applicable terms and conditions and other agreements;
  * in the event of a corporate transaction, such as a merger, reorganization, or acquisition, in which event your Personal Information may be transferred to the acquiring company;
  * in aggregated or other non-personally identifiable form; and/or
  * in accordance with your consent.

If you wish to opt out of any of the data sharing practices described in this section, please contact us as described in the below Contact Us section.

#### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”), on certain of our Online Services. Google Analytics uses cookies to collect information such as how often you visit our Online Services, what pages you visit within our Online Services, and what other sites you visited prior to coming to our Online Services. We use the information provided by Google Analytics to improve our Online Services. For more information regarding how Google collects, uses, and shares your information please visit http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of our Online Services. By using our Online Services, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google as specified herein. To provide users more choice on how their data is collected by Google Analytics, Google developed the Optout Browser Add-on: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en. By installing this Add-on, no information is being sent to Google Analytics.

#### California’s Do Not Track Notice

At this time, there is no worldwide uniform or consistent industry standard or definition for responding to, processing, or communicating Do Not Track signals. Thus, our Online Services are unable to respond to Do Not Track Signals.

Porsche does not allow third parties to collect Personal Information when you use our Online Services for their promotional purposes. We do use third party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics, to help us obtain and analyze information about your browsing and usage habits.

#### How We Protect Your Information

We implement reasonable technical, administrative, and physical safeguards to keep your Personal Information secure. For example, when you submit sensitive Personal Information, such as credit card information, through our Online Services, we utilize secure sockets layer (SSL) encryption technology. We also request that our third-party service providers use commercially reasonable security measures to protect your information from unauthorized access or use. However, no data transmission is guaranteed as 100% secure.

#### Submissions and User Generated Content

Unless governed by separate terms identified at the time of submission, all suggestions, materials, remarks, or other intellectual property (e.g., ideas, experiences, and photos) you communicate or submit to us (“Submissions”) will be considered nonconfidential and non-proprietary. Porsche shall have no obligation of any kind with respect to such Submissions and shall be free to use and distribute Submissions for any purposes, without limitation of any kind.

Our Online Services and Social Media Pages allow you to post messages and submit content (e.g., comments, phots, blogs, postings, etc.), which may include your Personal Information. You are responsible for all actions resulting from any information, including Personal Information, which you post on our Online Services or Social Media Pages. Please remember that any information you post becomes public information, is not subject to this Privacy Policy, and Porsche is not responsible for the results of such postings.

#### E-mail Security

"Phishing" is a scam designed to steal your Personal Information. If you receive an e-mail that looks like it is from us asking you for your Personal Information, please notify us as provided below in the Contact Us section.

#### Children’s Privacy

Our Online Services are not intended for use by children under 13. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13 without parental or guardian consent. Please contact us via the Contact Information provided below if you believe we may have collected such information without parental or guardian consent or other than in a manner authorized by law, and we will work to delete it.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, you may contact us at 1-800-PORSCHE, by sending an e-mail to [privacy@porsche.us](mailto:privacy@porsche.us), or by mail to Porsche Cars North America, Inc., One Porsche Drive, Atlanta, Georgia 30354, Attn: Privacy/Legal Department.

#### Your Acceptance of Our Privacy Policy

By using our Online Services, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, and you agree to adhere to the terms and conditions posted on our Online Services under “Legal notice.” If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not access or use our Online Services or submit any Personal Information to us.

#### Porsche Financial Services Privacy Notice

As a potential future Porsche Financial Services customer, we want you to know how Porsche Financial Services may share your personal information. The following links will direct you to their Privacy Notice, which explains how and with whom Porsche Financial Services may share your information, and the ways in which you can limit this sharing once you become a Porsche Financial Services customer.

If you are a California resident, click [here](https://files3.porsche.com/filestore/download/usa/none/privacypolicy-californiaoptoutform/default/2ceba4c3-8a11-11e6-9f1b-0019999cd470/Privacy-Policy-California-Privacy-Act-Opt-Out-Form.pdf) to view or print the Privacy Notice.

If you are a resident of any other state, click [here](https://files1.porsche.com/filestore/download/usa/none/privacypolicy-pfs/default/33ec1314-8a11-11e6-9f1b-0019999cd470/Privacy-Policy-Porsche-Financial-Service.pdf) to view or print the Privacy Notice.

#### Changes to the Privacy Policy

Porsche reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so you should review it frequently for changes. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post such changes here at http://www.porsche.com/usa/privacy-policy/. Your continued use of our Online Services and/or provision of your Personal Information after such posting constitute your acceptance of such changes. If we make a change to this Privacy Policy that, in our sole discretion, materially affects the use or disclosure of your Personal Information, a notice will be posted at http://www.porsche.com/usa with a link to the updated Privacy Policy. Please contact us as described in the Contact Us section if you would like information regarding any changes.

Effective Date: January 12, 2015 Copyright © 2015 Porsche Cars North America, Inc.

To request a summary of the changes made to the last version dated December 1, 2012, please contact us as described above.
